# Adam Gorski

# **Data Scientist**

Oakland, CA (509) 868-2147 adam.g.gorski@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/adamggorski github.com/goughgorski

Data scientist specializing in complex modeling using unstructured text data and social graph data.

Demonstrated ability throughout the data science value chain, from Data Engineering through Visualization, Analysis, and Experimentation, to building and putting into production Predictive Models. Cultivates good communication through good data, and vice versa.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Amitree, San Francisco, CA - Data Scientist

MARCH 2018 - PRESENT

Constructed, deployed, and scaled into production a suite of models and functions to surface multi-contact smart folder suggestions to 40k users

- Built Ruby tool to access Gmail API and construct corpus of 600k user-labeled messages
- Restructured data granularity and trained contact-level classifier
- Estimated dyad-level classifier with 97% accuracy to user labels
- Programmed complex boolean function in R to combine dyads into groups to serve as user suggestions in the product

Developed automated, real-time data visualizations of user cohort metrics

- Built SQL queries for transforming and aggregating user data
- Created Tableau dashboards to guide product decisions

# **University of San Francisco** - Adjunct Professor

AUGUST 2019 - PRESENT

 Courses: Data Science for Applied Economics, Graduate Econometrics, The Global Economy

# GreatSchools, Oakland, CA - Lead Data Scientist

AUGUST 2016 - MARCH 2018

Led data operations across the organization, pipeline to production

- Built and sustained R-based data analytics infrastructure to maximize scalability and flexibility across various national and state-level inputs
- Productized output quality through comprehensive analytical framework and QA process, relying on R, SQL, Unix Shell, and Ruby languages
- Managed and supervised Data Science team

#### **SKILLS**

- Data Analysis
- Predictive Modeling
- Statistics/Probability
- Causal Inference
- Experimentation
- Machine Learning
- Parameter Interpretation
- Visualization
- Instruction
- Relational Databases
- NLP (word2vec, STM, NER)
- R programming and production
- SQI
- Tableau
- Unix
- Git
- AWS

#### **EDUCATION**

University of California, Berkeley

MPP

University of San Francisco

MA, Economics BA, Economics